Evarts G. Loomis Company Collection of Hydraulic Sheeter Drawings
Evarts G. Loomis Company Collection of Hydraulic Sheeter Drawings
1919-1958
Evarts G. Loomis Company
18 items.
Collection consists of copies of 16 drawings, a materials list, and instructions for installation, operations and maintenance related to a hydraulic sheeter.
2663503
Biographical History
Evarts G. Loomis Company of Newark, NJ.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Evarts G. Loomis Company Collection of Hydraulic Sheeter Drawings consists of copies of 16 drawings, a materials list, and instructions for installation, operations and maintenance related to a hydraulic sheeter. The drawings have either the Evarts G. Loomis Company or Arlington Works name. One drawing is labeled Standard Pyroxoloid Company.
Arrangement of the Collection
None.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing. In particular, see also
Standard Pyroxoloid Company
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; Evarts G. Loomis Company -- Archives.; Arlington Works.; Standard Pyroxoloid Corporation.;; Plastics industry and trade.; Hydraulic machinery.; Plastics machinery.; Mechanical drawing; Drawings (visual works); Hydraulic engineers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008.
Inventory
- Drawings
  - Standard Pyroxoloid Corporation, Building 16 Floorspace, 26 x 35" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Roller table for holding out sheets of Pyralin, 1924; 30 x 42" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Hydraulic sheeter dash pot lever traced from Arlington Works drawing, 15.5 x 21" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Hydraulic Sheeter leather packing, 1919; rev. 1925; 0.5 x 16" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Double acting hydraulic sheeter valve, 1941; 21 x 30" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Hydraulic sheeter drive, 1920; 15 x 20" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Hydraulic sheeter right left hard stop, 1920; 15 x 21" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Hydraulic sheeter low pressure control valve, 1919; 31 x 42" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Hydraulic sheeter low pressure control valve, 1919; 15 x 21" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Hydraulic valve, 1924; 11 x 17" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Valve pod bearing, 1919; 10 x 15" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Arlington Works. Hydraulic sheeter, 1919; 30 x 42" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Hydraulic sheeter, 1936; 22 x 35" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Hydraulic sheeter, 1936; 22 x 35" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Hydraulic sheeter, 1934; 22 x 37" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Hydraulic sheeter, 1932; 11 x 34" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Hydraulic sheeter materials list no. 28, 1928; rev. 1947 (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Evarts G. Loomis. Instructions for installation, operation & maintenance of Loomis Special 36" Hydraulic Sheeter Machine no. 28, circa 1957 (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)